genbook.com 2015-03-19

# Privacy Policy | Genbook

Dated August 18, 2013

Genbook, Inc. owns and provides various websites, mobile websites, services, and software that facilitate online scheduling and management of appointments (collectively, the “Services”). Genbook, Inc. respects your privacy and values your trust. In this Privacy Policy, we may refer to Genbook, Inc. as “Genbook,” “us,” or “we.” “Business User” shall refer to any business using the Services for online scheduling and appointment management purposes. “Consumer” shall refer to an end consumer using the Services to schedule or manage an appointment, provide feedback or submit a review, or utilize any other aspect of the Services. “You” shall refer to both Consumers and Business Users. The following Privacy Policy outlines how Genbook will treat information as you use the Services. BY USING THE SERVICES, YOU ACCEPT THE TERMS SET FORTH IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND IN OUR TERMS OR USE.

This Privacy Policy and the TRUSTe certification covers our collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through our website [www.genbook.com](http://www.genbook.com/) and our mobile website m.genbook.com. The use of information collected through the Services shall be limited to the purpose of providing the Services.

Genbook has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this Privacy Policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/program_requirements_website_privacy.html) and the [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/trusted-cloud/index.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us. If you are not satisfied with our response you can [contact TRUSTe](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

Genbook reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to change, modify, update, add, or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time, with or without notice to you. Please check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes. Your continued use of the Services after the posting of any changes to the Privacy Policy will signify your acceptance of those changes.

If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your Genbook account), by posting a message in your Genbook account, or by means of a prominent notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Personally Identifiable Information (PII)

PII is any piece of information which can be traced back to a specific individual user and thus potentially be used to uniquely identify, contact, or locate that specific individual. Examples of PII we collect include names, telephone numbers, address, date of birth, credit card numbers and other unique identifiers. In no event will Genbook use PII to market the services of a third party, or sell or transfer PII to third parties, or otherwise provide third parties with access thereto, except as specifically provided in this Privacy Policy and/or in our applicable Terms of Use.

We do not ask you for, access or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while using our mobile Web site.

**Consumers.**  If a Consumer chooses to schedule an appointment with a Business User, the Consumer may elect to provide information including, but not limited to, that Consumer’s name, telephone number, and email address (collectively “Consumer Information”), that may be Personally Identifiable Information. We may also collect credit card information from Consumers in circumstances where a Business User has decided that it requires such information to be collected from Consumers scheduling appointments with it through the Services. We may also collect user submitted information including but not limited to ratings & reviews of businesses and service providers with whom the submitting Consumer has interacted through the Services, and any responses or other postings by a Business User.

We also collect Consumer Information on behalf of Business Users through our Web site and mobile Web site. 

Consumers can access, correct, amend or delete certain of their Consumer Information after registering for an account at the Genbook Customer Center. A Consumer seeking to correct, amend or delete inaccurate Consumer Information collected by Genbook in respect of appointments scheduled with a specific Genbook Business User can also direct their queries to that Business User. If the Business User requests that we delete specific Consumer Information, we will respond to that request within 30 business days.

**Business Users.**  When a Business User registers to use the Services, we may ask that Business User to provide business information including the business name, type of business, email address, telephone number, and street address (“Business Information”). We may also ask Business Users to provide a valid credit card number and billing address so that we can process any payments for use of the Services by such Business User, pursuant to the Business User Terms of Use. Business Users, as registered users of the Services, may modify amend or deactivate their account information at any time by accessing the “My Account” section of their Genbook account when such Business User is logged into the Services or by contacting us.

We also collect Consumer Information from Business Users through our website and mobile website.

We also collect information from Business Users about their staff, such as name, email address and phone number. If staff information has been collected about you and you wish to change or have that information no longer used please contact the relevant Business User.

When a Business User uses our refer-a-friend program we will automatically send that Business User’s referrals a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. Genbook stores this referral information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. If you no longer wish to have your information used for this purpose please contact us

When using our mobile website we will collect your mobile device’s operating system and device type for the purposes of customer support and improving the Services.

You should be aware that if you upload, post, and/or distribute to the Services material, including but not limited to, Personally Identifiable Information, questions, feedback, reviews, data, comments, ratings, suggestions, information, text, data, software, sounds, photographs, podcasts, audio, audiovisual, video, images, graphics, messages and other content or materials of any nature (“User Submitted Materials”), those materials and the substantive information contained in them may be accessible by third parties. To request removal of your personal information from our open forums, contact us. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

In the event that Genbook discovers that personal information has been or is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

**Use of Personally Identifiable Information.**  We do not intentionally provide PII to third parties except where you provide PII when scheduling or managing an appointment through the Services, when registering to use the Services as a Business User, managing appointments and clients through our mobile Web site or to indicate interest in services advertised by one of the businesses bookable through the Services, or as otherwise outlined in this Privacy Policy. In any of the above situations, we may provide that information to the appropriate Consumer, Business User or advertiser so that they may attempt to schedule or manage an appointment or provide you with information regarding the advertised products or services about which you inquired.

If a Consumer provides any Consumer Information or User Submitted Materials to the Services that are relevant to a Business User with whom that Consumer schedules an appointment or otherwise transacts through the Services, Genbook reserves the right to provide such Business User with the relevant Consumer Information and/or User Submitted Materials for purposes of managing the appointment and/or transaction with such Consumer, whether or not such information is Personally Identifiable Information.

Pursuant to our Business User Terms of Use, we may provide relevant Business Information including but not limited to business name, address, contact phone number and scheduling website address to third parties in order to maximize the exposure of Genbook Business Users online and the number of appointments scheduled through the Services. If you do not wish to have your personal information shared with these third parties you may log into your account and select the appropriate settings or contact us.

We may use PII and any other information provided by a Business User or a Consumer through the Services for internal purposes, such as sales, human resources, marketing, and administration. We may share this information with third parties who provide us with administrative services, credit card processing services to process payments and email services to send out emails on our behalf. We will share your personal information only as is necessary for the third parties to provide their services. The third parties’ use of that information will be governed by their privacy policies.

If you or any other user of the Services sends an email or provides an email address to Genbook for any reason, we reserve the right to retain that email address to use to send future notifications in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the applicable Genbook Terms of Use.

Information and User Submitted Materials provided by a Business User on its profile or elsewhere on the Services will be accessible by Consumers. Information and User Submitted Materials provided by a Consumer, including any personally identifiable information provided when such Consumer schedules an appointment through the Services, will be made available to the Business User with whom the Consumer is scheduling an appointment.

When collecting personal information under the direction of its Business Users, Genbook has no direct relationship with the Consumers whose personal information it processes other than as outlined in this privacy policy. Genbook works with its Business Users to help them provide notice to their customers concerning the purpose for which personal information is collected.

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or is needed to provide you our Services. We will retain and use your information as is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Non-personally identifiable information is information that, by itself, cannot be tracked to a specific individual. Examples of non-personally identifiable information include, but are not limited to, the type of internet browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, your IP address, the time and date of your use of the Services, and whether or not you clicked on hypertext links within the Services. We may collect non-personally identifiable information while you use the Services.

### Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information

We may use the non-personally identifiable information to generate user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners. If we provide any such information to others, we will provide such information in the aggregate only and will not include any personally identifiable information about any individual users. We may also use the non-personally identifiable information to generate statistics that we may provide to you and to other businesses using the Services, including, for example, the number of appointments in a certain time period. We also may provide non-personally identifiable information to contractors so that they can perform services for us.

### Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer’s hard drive and mobile device to identify your computer or device to our servers. In some instances, we link the information we store in cookies to personally identifiable information you submit while on our site or mobile Web site. If your browser is configured to accept cookies, we will use cookies to recognize your computer or mobile device when you visit or use the Services so that we can provide you with a more personalized and streamlined experience and improve the quality of the Services. If you wish, you can configure your browser to block cookies. In order to accept and manage appointments, reservations, or bookings made by Consumers through the Services, however, you must have cookies enabled.

Advertisements of third-party advertisers may be displayed on the Services. If you choose to click on a third-party advertisement or link, we may provide non-personally identifiable information to the owning advertiser, advertising network and/or web publisher. Also, any such advertiser, advertising network or web publisher may use cookies or other technologies to collect information when you are visiting their web sites. The information advertisers or other third parties collect is governed by their individual privacy policies. Genbook does not take responsibility nor can guarantee the content of such third-party privacy policies. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by [clicking here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Clear Gifs

We employ or our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information. 

### Log Files

As is true of most Web sites, we and our third party tracking-utility partners gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site and mobile site, to track users’ movements around the site and mobile site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

### Notifications

We may use such information to send you email messages and other notifications relating to the Services and your use of the Services. We reserve the right to notify you through e-mail, or notices posted on the Genbook websites, as determined by Genbook in our discretion. In addition we offer Business Users the opportunity to choose to receive text message alerts through their account settings. Please be aware that if you choose to receive text alerts, applicable carrier rates may apply. By using the Services, you consent to receiving such notifications.

Business Users may opt-out of receiving notifications regarding appointments through the Services by logging into their Genbook account and changing the notification settings; opting-out of such notifications, however, will limit the effectiveness of the Services. Notwithstanding the foregoing, neither Business Users nor Consumers may opt-out of receiving notifications relating to support of the Services or other notices as required by law. If we have provided any third party with your personal information, you will have to contact the third-party directly with any opt-out request.

When Business Users sign up for an account we will use their information to send them our newsletter. If you wish to no longer receive our newsletter you may follow the unsubscribe instructions contained in each of the emails you receive.

### Links to Other Web Sites

Our site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Genbook. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

### Information Collected from Third Party Sites and Services

The Services may incorporate or integrate with third party websites and services (collectively, “Third Party Sites and Services”). Such Third Party Services may supply us with PII and other information about you that you provided to the applicable third party. The applicable third party's privacy policy governs its collection, use and disclosure of such information. We use and disclose any such information supplied to us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Testimonials

We post customer testimonials on our website which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you would like to request the removal of your testimonial from the site you may contact us.

### Schedule and Appointment Information

Genbook will not share a Business User schedule with anyone, except to the extent necessary to allow Consumers to browse, schedule and manage appointments. We will not share a Consumer’s personal schedule information with anyone except the Business User with whom such Consumer schedules an appointment. Each Business User will be able to access and view only the schedule for that business, and only information relating to appointments for that business.

### Other Sharing of Information

We may release information when necessary to comply with the law or a court order or an investigation. We also may release information to law enforcement to protect our rights, property, or other interests, including those of our customers or users or to prevent illegal activities or violations of our Terms of Use.

In the event that we, in whole or in part, establish a partnership with another company, or are acquired by or merged with another company, information we collect may be transferred to the partner or the acquiring or merging company at time such merger, acquisition, or partnership is closed and to the extent necessary to fulfill our obligations under such merger, acquisition, or partnership.

### Social Media Features

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant Feature.

### Child Protection

We do not offer services to, or target, persons under the age of 13. In compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, we will purge any information we receive from people we believe to be children under 13 from our database and cancel the corresponding accounts.

### Security

We have implemented commercially reasonable technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure (when you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our website or our mobile website, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL), but we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. We cannot ensure the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet, and we accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure of such information. You acknowledge that you provide your personal information at your own risk. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us.

Please contact us if you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy.
